## **Curriculum Vitae**

Richard Murray
3 St Austell Drive
Bury
BL8 4EY

Date of birth: 11/05/1989 Home: 01204882993 Mobile: 07491689103

Email: richardmurray11@hotmail.co.uk

Nationality: British

#### **Profile:**

I am a confident and adaptable individual who enjoys solving problems and is used to working under pressure. I have a flexible approach to work and have always been a self-starter, fast learner and quick to adapt to new environments.

I have outstanding interpersonal skills and have been commended on my telephone manner and ability to handle difficult members of the public and stay calm under pressure. I have a passion for technology and a thirst for knowledge in the sector, as proven by my current training in Microsoft Windows Server 2012 and in the past with Microsoft MCSA. I have expertise working with a very wide spectrum of IT technologies including Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows 10, Office 365, G Suite (Google Apps), VMWare and vCentre, MacOS, Windows Server 2003/2008 (including Active Directory, Microsoft Exchange and DHCP), Symantec Backup Exec, Antivirus (McAfee & Avast) as well as plenty of experience with the hardware side of I.T. including Ghost Imaging of HDD, Cloning of HDD, memory, video cards, setup of laptops, telephony, iPads, printers and desktops for large project rollouts across large organisations including the NHS and GMCA as well as skills in network & server administration such as utilising DNS, Command Line, Group Policy, Active Directory Management (Domain Services) and DHCP.

I have great experience supporting and deploying all software across many organisations including G Suite at RM Education, Windows 10 at RM Education and GMCA and Office 365 at GMCA, RM Education and Rochdale Council.

I have run these deployment projects by myself normally using tools such as SCCM or RM's own software tool called CC4 (RM Management software). I would also test all manner of applications before roll out phase and document and log changes made with management as well as support the end users after rollout phase was complete. With Office 365, I would demonstrate the software to the end

user as well as resolve any technical issues and advise the how and why the issue occurred in the first place, therefore stopping the issue from re-occurring for that user, OneDrive being a popular tool used to store and share data across organisations. As well as this I would also demonstrate Sharepoint to end users at Greater Manchester Police, where it was used day in, day out by officers and detectives for storing data across the organisation. I am used to training apprentices and helpdesk colleagues through my work at the Police as well as at the NHS and RM Education and taking the lead on support and projects also.

I approach all my work with a mature attitude and pride myself on my ability to keep to any set deadlines or finish tasks early wherever possible. I have always been passionate about computers, their inner workings and combining this with my love for problem solving makes IT work my natural strong point.

### **Education:**

St. Gabriel's R.C High School, Bury

2000 - 2005

GCSEs: English Language (C), English Literature (C), Mathematics (C), Business Studies (C), Religion (C), Drama (C)

Bury College 2006 – 2007 Certificate in Business Administration Level 2 Word Processing Business Studies

Manchester College (Central Park Campus) October 2013 - November 2013 Cisco CCNA: Exploration (Introduction to Cisco Systems)

Microsoft MCSA Burnley College September 2015 -November 2015 Administrating Windows Server 2012

## **Employment History:**

March 2019 – Present Windows 10 Engineer Manchester City Council

Covering all aspects of the Windows 10 Project, from testing applications, documentation, deployment, to rollout of devices including desktops and laptops as well as assisting project members with daily tasks including the Application Packager on the team. Working across various projects including a library upgrade as well as desktop tower devices with

complex application needs, I would work with other project members on planning out the project so that it would suit the needs and wants of the end user. As well as this I would sit with users testing all applications that would work and if not then provide breakfix support there and then. I would also be an escalation point of contact for the Desktop Support team and 3<sup>rd</sup> Line Support Team within the Council with any queries and providing results and fixes for any Windows 10 enquiries alongside the rest of the team.

Working closely with the Application Support team as well as the Desktop Support team and 3<sup>rd</sup> Line Support teams within the Council on rectifying any issues before they would be logged as a Problem on the system and manually upgrade devices, add items to, fix faults or utilise toolsets such as SCCM, Windows Server technologies, RegEdit and Active Directory.

This Windows 10 Project was successfully completed as of September 2019 and around 98% of Council workers across the Council have now been upgraded to Windows 10.

# March 2018 – March 2019 IT Consultant/IT Engineer RM Education (Salford)

Working for Managed Service Provider RM Education, I am currently supporting two different schools in the Salford region, Buile Hill Visual Arts College and Ellesmere Park High School. I manage the IT systems at both schools. This does include both the servers and network environment. There is also a networked printing service built in that I also manage. I maintain the storage environment across both schools, so this includes running backups and data storage as well as network patching and proxy server and SSL. At Buile Hill High School I also manage an IT Apprentice who is completing his course. I would help train him up both in the field and help him with his apprenticeship in the process. AV support is also provided such as for projectors, sound systems and large screen displays. IT support and setup at these schools is also included for devices such as iPads, iMacs, Chrome devices, laptops, desk phones, mobile phones as well as other devices. I provide software support across OS like Windows 7, MacOS and Windows 10. I have just finished running a Windows 10 deployment project across the site and an Office 2016 upgrade on all devices alongside a SIMS upgrade for all staff devices, so I am used to dealing with multiple projects concurrently. These upgrades are now complete and are all working for staff. I have since been moved on to support Ellesmere Park High School where I have just finished rolling out both Windows 10 and Office 365 across the school during the Summer school holiday before both the staff and students come back. This work was undertaken by myself. I would test and deploy the Office 365 environment and gather feedback from colleagues based at other schools and test other applications that are used in the education environment in Windows 10 and ensured that everything works as it should, if it does not I would add Windows Updates required, patch software, run command line scripts, change software settings or replace software applications with newer versions until they all worked as they should. The project is almost over and everything is now working ready for the new school year.

November 2017 – March 2018 2nd Line Technician/IT Engineer The Manchester College/LTE Group Working across several sites as an onsite/field support engineer at the Openshaw campus, Harpurhey campus, Wythenshawe campus and many others, I would provide break fix support to staff at all levels as well as for students across the College premises. In this role I would be passed jobs from the Helpdesk team with who I also worked with also doing Helpdesk Support at their main office headquarters at Central Park as and when required. Frequently installing, configuring, fixing and testing software as well as network patching, resolving printing issues, re-imaging and deploying desktops, Virtual Desktops (VDIs - zero clients and thin clients) and laptops, server administration (Exchange, Active Directory, Windows Server, NetTools etc), telephony setups, dealing with mobile phone issues, office movies, maintaining and supporting the projectors and interactive white boards used in classrooms and board room meetings. Utilise SCCM as well as Vmware Horizon to resolve certain technical faults. SLA and ITIL structured environment.

April 2017 - October 2017 IT Engineer - Contractor Greater Manchester Fire & Rescue Service

April 2017 - October 2017 ICT Deployment Engineer - Contractor Office of Greater Manchester Mayor

April 2017 - October 2017 IT Consultant - Contractor Greater Manchester Combined Authority

Working at Churchgate House as one of the two on site support engineers since the inception of the project Greater Manchester Combined Authority, which is an ongoing project to bring together and combine all of the public sector - Fire Service, Greater Manchester Police, all of the Greater Manchester Town Councils, the NHS, Waste Authority, Office of Police & Crime Commissioner and many others all of which are being governed by the Greater Manchester Mayor Andy Burnham; myself and my colleague were placed in charge of setting up, configuring and providing general day to day immediate IT support to people of all levels who run the public sector in the North West region. This would involve rolling out equipment to hundreds of staff, setting up desks with IT equipment such as monitors, stands, laptops, docking stations, printers, photocopiers, desktops, iPhones and desk phones as well as support these devices day in day out. Alongside this we would train and help familiarise staff joining with Windows 10 which we were rolling out across the building and do the same also for Office 365 (including OneDrive) and get staff comfortable with a cloud environment moving forward and demonstrate how to utilise all of the Office 365 applications such as for presentations or sharing data with their colleagues as well as resolve any technical faults as they arise with Office 365. Some of the areas were mainly used as hot desk environments so as people came in we would provide support to staff from all of these organisations including those coming in to use the meeting rooms in the building such as supporting AV equipment for presentations or resolving issues with cabling or network issues. Support is also provided to all of the software that these organisations utilise including helping with VPN technologies such as DirectAccess, Cisco AnyConnect and Citrix Receiver. Tools used but not limited to Microsoft

Exchange, Computer Management, Print Management, Active Directory, Citrix Receiver, and many others.

January 2017 - April 2017 IT Engineer (Projects) - Contractor Rochdale Borough Council

General 2nd Line Support working on a large scale IT Project across Rochdale Borough Council working alongside one other engineer in this role, we set up new equipment for members of staff at all levels wether they be Councillors, support staff or setting up equipment for use in the libraries in the area which is the second project we are working on in tandem. Also as a part of setting up equipment in the libraries we also are responsible for setting up IT security on these desktops using certain software. As well as this we help to resolve any ongoing faults as part of this project if and when they arise. In this role we generally set up tablets, desktops, port replicators (dual screens) and laptops as well as take part in office moves this generally involves setting up network ports via network patching and coordinating this with the 3rd Level team. Helpdesk Support sometimes will escalate faults to us as well to deal with whilst we sort out equipment for the same team or whilst we are the in the area. Technologies used are Microsoft based such as Office 2010, Office 365 (for sharing and storing data), Active Directory Management, software deployment tools such as SCCM (ConfigMgr), Service Manager Console and others. This was an ongoing contract due to end at the end of March due to it being a short term project.

October 2015 - January 2017 IT Customer Service Officer Greater Manchester Police

General 1st Line Support that included answering the phone and frequently deal with high priority IT support for police officers and police staff across the Greater Manchester and Lancashire areas. Remote support often including server support, application support and network support. Windows XP, Windows 7, Windows Server 2003 & 2012. Active Directory, DHCP, Microsoft Exchange, IBM Lotus Notes and backup solutions. Prioritise workload and work as a part of a large IT team. Installation and setting up of IT software and equipment would also be required in this role including phones, printers, laptops and desktops.

April 2015 - September 2015
Network Engineer/IT Support
IT Department
J Rosenthal & Son Ltd

General 2nd Line/3rd Line IT support as there was just two of us in the I.T. department (myself and Darren Lee who was the IT Manager) including break fix support such as rebuilding PCs, printers and laptops, also cloning hard drives

and setting up new equipment for deployment, fixing IT equipment as well as ordering and setting up IT supplies such as printers, Windows phones, iPads and laptops and frequently provide desktop support to users. Windows 7 OS, Windows Server 2003 & 2012 OS, VMWare/ vCentre for managing virtual servers and desktops, fixing printers, maintaining Servers and Networks, frequent office moves, new starter setups and network tasks that are regularly provided in my role. I would provide Server Administration In this role I would frequently use Active Directory in my administration role, including to set up new starters. As our department was small, with only two of us in this department, I would frequently be providing 3rd Line Support to users which included Network Administration whereby I would be maintaining and testing the network, maintain network firewall, helping with wiring new network access points and assigning or removing IP addresses to certain machines via DHCP. I would also provide 3rd Line Support/Server Administration with Microsoft Exchange, Symantec Backup Exec, Windows Server 2003 and Server 2012.

In this role, I would also be rolling out Windows 7 and Avast Antivirus software to all users and maintain the security of the computers. In this role we used the remote desktop software Kaseya or TeamViewer 10 to connect to PCs and provide Remote Support to users in other locations. Working at both Headquarters and at the warehouse, I would frequently provide general support to all users, including the managing director, as and when required in an efficient and timely manner.

September 2014 March 2015
EPMA IT Project
Engineer/ IT
Technical Engineer (6 Month Contract)
Pennine Acute Hospital Trust (NHS)

General 2nd Line IT support including hardware/breakfix support such as rebuilding PCs and laptops which would include imaging hard drives and testing new equipment for deployment, fixing IT equipment as well as setting up an extensive number of IT equipment such as printers, phones, UPS batteries and laptops and frequently provide desktop support to users. Windows 7 OS, XP OS, fixing and setting up printers, blood label printers (Zebra printers), office moves and network patching are also tasks that are regularly provided in my role.

Being part of a projects team also meant I had to plan and set up various equipment for use on this EPMA project, which is a big project being rolled out across all of the wards at the four sites at the Pennine Acute Hospitals Trust (North Manchester General, Fairfield General, Rochdale Infirmary and Royal Oldham Hospital). Working alongside a big IT team based mainly at North Manchester General, I would regularly help in the Breakfix Engineer/IT Engineer team, reconfiguring and repairing faulty workstations and laptops for use in offices and wards when needed, sometimes in an emergency. Using various administrative tools such as frequently using the likes of Active Directory (Groups, Domains, Password resets, Rights, Privileges etc), Lansweeper, McAfee Encryption Endpoint (IT Security), DameWare Mini Remote Control,

Remote Desktop and reserving IP addresses on Servers is also required in my current role.

Medical Records Clerk
May 2013-September 2014
North Manchester General Hospital

Data entry on to a database (PAS), filing, find patient files for clinics and filing, portering, email systems, maintain booking system, answering incoming calls, deal with incoming and outgoing members of staff with queries in the library, generally help other members of the team.

February 2013 -April 2013 Administrator (Temporary) Business Solutions Bury College

Data entry on to a database, mail merge, regularly use Microsoft packages such as Word and Excel, filing, working on reception, email systems, book appointments,

answering incoming calls, help the recruitment team, admin team and Business Development team with various tasks, deal with incoming and outgoing members of staff.

June 2012 – December 2012 ICT Support (Voluntary) Town Hall Bury Council

I contacted Bury Council in order to get hands on experience and training in a busy and diverse environment. I have been working alongside the rest of the IT team at

Bury Council which encompasses IT across Bury from leisure centres to Children's Services and involves going out to all different locations to troubleshoot computer problems and set up new systems. I worked there in the mornings, on a voluntary basis and worked in my paid job at Alpha Hospitals alongside it in the late afternoon shift. I have experience in the following:

Fixing faulty computers - problem solving including speeding up slow computers, decrementing computer, disk clean up, getting rid of viruses, troubleshooting etc.

Changing internal components such as hard drives, CD-Drives, memor y, BIOs batteries. Setting up of laptops, desktops and printers. Working on network servers, as well as setting up network points and installing relevant software. Active Directory, Ultra VNC, Remote Desktop, Network Setup (TCP/IP), Microsoft packages, Active Sync. Rebuilding computers, setting up office equipment, improving performance of computers and dealing with technical faults.

Interests: Traveling, Technology, Socialising, Listening To Music, Long Walks With My Dog, Martial Arts, Movies, Eating Out.

References: Russell Fish – Senior Business Analyst Manchester City Council	Lisa Christopherson - Customer Experience Manager
r.fish@manchester.gov.uk	Lisa.Christopherson@accessplc.com